- I remember one time coming out of a complex meeting
-我記得有一次來自一次複雜的會議
that had a lot of action items that I needed to capture
中，其中有很多行動項目，我需要捕獲
and put into an email for the team.
並將其放入團隊的電子郵件中。
I was dreading it.
我很害怕
And then I thought I should use AI
然後我想我應該使
for a first draft.
用 AI 做第一個草稿。
It was great.
真是太棒了
I didn't have to worry about capturing the action items.
我不必擔心捕捉動作項目。
I didn't have to worry about the formatting,
我不必擔心格式化的問題，一
and once I put my own touches
旦我做了自己的操作並
and reviewed carefully what AI had created,
仔細審查 AI 所創建的內容，我發
I sent off the email, and it saved me a lot of time.
送了電子郵件，這節省了我很多時間。
AI can sometimes feel like magic.
AI 有時會感覺像魔法。
It is so much power to do amazing things in seconds.
在幾秒鐘內完成驚人的事情是如此強大的力量。
When I get an impressive AI result, I'm almost expecting
當我得到令人印象深刻的 AI 結果時，我
to hear applause in the background,
幾乎希望在後台聽到掌聲，
but of course, AI isn't magic.
但當然，AI 並不是魔術。
It's a computer program that, like others, has capabilities
它是一種計算機程序，與其他程序一樣，具有功能
and limitations.
和限制。
Understanding how AI works can help you get
了解 AI 的運作方式可以幫
the most out of it.
助您充分利用它。
I'm gonna walk you through the top things you need
我將引導您了解您需要了解的關於
to know about AI, and don't worry,
AI 的主要事情，不用擔心，
I'll do without all the tech jargon.
我將不用所有技術術語來完成。
First things first.
第一事先。
Let's get on the same page.
讓我們來說同一個頁面。
When we say AI,
當我們說 AI 時，除了
what are we really talking about beyond the buzzword?
流行詞之外，我們真正在談論什麼？
You probably already know that AI stands
您可能已經知道 AI 代表
for artificial intelligence.
人工智能。
Artificial intelligence is the concept
人工智能是構
of building intelligent machines
建智能機器的概念，
that can do things like reasoning through a problem
它們可以執行諸如解決問題
and providing recommendations.
並提供建議等事情。
But how does it do that?
但是它如何做到這一點？
Well, within the world of AI,
好吧，在 AI 世界中，
you have something called models.
你有一個叫做模型的東西。
AI models are computer programs that are trained on tons
AI 模型是針對大量
of data, like articles, images, or videos.
數據（例如文章，圖像或視頻）進行訓練的計算機程序。
The model finds patterns in the data,
模型在資料中尋找模式，
and then is able to apply those patterns
然後能夠將這些模式套用
to new situations like making predictions
到新情況，例如做預測
or generating new content.
或產生新內容。
This process, called training,
這個程序稱為培訓，可
helps the model improve over time,
以幫助模型隨著時間的推移
and this isn't some futuristic technology.
改進，而這不是未來派技術。
Think of your email spam filter.
想想您的電子郵件垃圾郵件過濾器。
It uses massive amounts of data
它使用大量數據來幫助
to help sort emails you want
您從不想要的電子郵件
from the emails you don't want, you know, spam.
中排序您想要的電子郵件，您知道的垃圾郵件。
Every time you mark something as spam,
每當您標記某些內容為垃圾郵件時，
it learns from that and gets better and better over time.
它都會從中學習，並隨著時間的推移而變得越來越好。
But what happens when your spam filter gets it wrong
但是，當您的垃圾郵件過濾器發生錯誤並
and an important email gets lost?
且重要的電子郵件丟失時會發生什麼？
The answer may lie in the model's training data.
答案可能在模型的訓練數據中。
This is the data that AI learns from.
這是 AI 從中學習的數據。
Let's look at another example.
讓我們看一下另一個例子。
Say, a food distributor trains an AI model
假設，食品分銷商訓練 AI 模型，
to sort apples from other fruit.
將蘋果從其他水果中分類。
This model's training data includes thousands of images
該模型的訓練數據包括
of apples, enabling the model to recognize, well, apples.
數千張蘋果圖像，使模型能夠識別蘋果。
But what happens if the training data
但是，如果訓練數據
only included images of red apples?
僅包含紅蘋果圖像，會發生什麼？
This might make the model less accurate at identifying
這可能會使模型在識別其他
other types of apples, like green or yellow.
類型的蘋果方面不準確，例如綠色或黃色。
As a result, the food distributor
因此，食品分銷商最終可
might end up sorting apples incorrectly,
能會錯誤地分類蘋果，導
causing them to lose money
致蘋果損失金錢
and waste perfectly good apples.
並浪費完美好的蘋果。
A model's training data shapes what it does.
模型的訓練資料會形成模型的工作。
It's also one reason why one model may produce
這也是一個模型可能產生與另一個模型不
different results from another.
同的結果的原因。
A second reason is the model architecture itself.
第二個原因是模型架構本身。
How a model is programmed
模型的編程方式
and the rules it applies to its data
以及其應用於其數據
and learning may vary from model to model.
和學習的規則可能因模型而異。
Some AI models, like Gemini, learn from massive amounts
一些 AI 模型，例如 Gemini，從大量數據中學
of data that go way beyond images of fruit alone.
習，這些數據遠遠遠遠超出水果圖像。
With more data and training,
有了更多數據和培訓，模
a model can start doing some pretty amazing things.
型可以開始做一些非常令人驚嘆的事情。
It can understand a request
即使是第一次
even if it's the first time it's encountering
遇到這種
that type of request.
類型的請求，它也可以理解請求並回應它。
This advanced type of model is called a large language model
這種高級模型的模型被稱為大語言模
or an LLM for short.
型，簡稱為 LLM。
LLMs can learn so much
LLM 可以學到很多東西，
and get so good at predicting based on patterns
並且非常擅長根據模式進行預測，他們
that they can create entirely new content
可以創建完全新的內容，例
like blog posts or birthday haiku.
如博客文章或生日 haiku。
AI's ability to create something new is called Generative AI
AI 創造新東西的能力稱為生成 AI
or GenAI for short.
或簡稱 GenAI。
It gets even more amazing.
它變得更加令人驚嘆。
Some GenAI assistants are multimodal,
一些 GenAI 助理是多種模式的，
which is just a fancy way of saying they can work
這只是一種表示他們可以處理不僅僅是文本的一
with more than just text.
種花樣的方式。
They can understand and create images, videos,
他們可以理解和創建圖像，視頻
audio, and more.
，音頻等。
So you could upload a photo of a chart
因此，您可以上傳圖表的
and ask for a text summary of it
照片並要求其文本摘要，
or submit an audio recording of a meeting
或提交會議的音頻記錄
and have it turned into a list of action items.
並將其轉換為行動項目列表。
Or you could easily create compelling visuals
或者，您可以輕鬆地為您
for your website or client presentation.
的網站或客戶簡報創建引人注目的視覺效果。
Let's look at another way AI is evolving.
讓我們來看看 AI 進化的另一種方式。
You may have heard about AI Agents.
您可能聽說過 AI 代理程式。
What's that all about?
這是什麼意思？
Well, think of agents as systems
好吧，將代理程式視為系統
that combine the intelligence of advanced AI models
，它將先進 AI 模型的智慧
with access to tools like your calendar or email.
與存取行事曆或電子郵件等工具的存取功能相結合。
Instead of giving an agent a single task,
您可以將更廣泛的目標給代理人，而
you can give it a broader goal.
不是給代理人一個單一任務。
Then the agent can break that goal down into smaller steps
然後，代理人可以將目標分成更小的步驟，
and take action on your behalf, all under your control.
並代表您採取行動，這一切都在您的控制下。
For example, imagine telling an AI agent,
例如，想像一個人工智能代理人說：
"Organize a kickoff meeting for the Q3 marketing project
「下週與設計和銷售團隊與
with the design and sales teams for next week."
設計和銷售團隊組織第三季營銷項目的啟動會議。」
An AI agent could then check everyone's calendars
然後，AI 代理人可以檢查每個人
for a free slot,
的日曆以獲取免費
book a meeting room, draft a welcome email
位置，預訂會議室，草擬帶有專
with the project brief attached,
案簡介的歡迎電子郵件
and send out the calendar invitation.
，並發送日曆邀請。
It can handle all the tedious coordination, freeing the team
它可以處理所有繁瑣的協調，釋放團隊
to focus on the actual strategy for the meeting.
專注於會議的實際策略。
The opportunity there is not just answering your questions,
這裡有機會不僅是回答您的問題，
but actively helping you to accomplish your goals.
而且積極幫助您實現目標。
Okay, great, we've talked about what AI is, how it works,
好吧，很好，我們已經討論了 AI 是什麼，它的工作方式以
and some emerging capabilities.
及一些新興的功能。
This is crucial for you to be an informed user.
這對於您成為一個明智的用戶至關重要。
It allows you to make the most
它使您能夠充分利用
of AI's possibilities while understanding its limitations.
AI 的可能性，同時了解其限制。
Let's keep going.
讓我們繼續前進。